Rev. David S. Vatral

16531 Susquehanna Trail South, New Freedom, PA 17349 dvatral@trailnaz.org

SUMMARY

Blends a wide variety of pastoral leadership with experience in counseling and business to effectively minister to people in all walks of life. Committed to bringing new people to Christ, encouraging existing believers to deepen their relationships with God, and ministering to the community at large.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Trail Church of the Nazarene | New Freedom, PA

- Lead Pastor: 1999 Present
 - Preaching, Leading Worship Team, Teaching, Vision Casting, Baptisms, Communion, Weddings, Funerals, Community Outreach, Counseling, Leading Church Board, Problem Solving, Budgeting, Member District Credentials Board, Leadership Team, Ministry Assessment Center

Light and Life Christian Counseling / New Freedom, PA and York, PA

- Owner, Operator, Counselor: 2017-Present
 - Anxiety, Addictions, Children, Coaching, Couples, Depression, Family, Grief, Pornography, Pre-marriage

Cell: (717) 683-8971

Home: (717) 227-1322

- Business operations and administration
- Partnering with LifePath Christian Ministries, York PA, to provide counseling to the homeless and hurting

Williamson Bible Institute | York, PA

- Professor: 2000 Present
 - Teaching, Evaluating, Mentoring, Leadership training, Writing Lesson Plans, Creating Syllabus, Working with Nazarene Bible College

Gracious Promise Counseling Center | York, PA

- Counselor: 2014 2017
 - Anxiety, Addictions, Children, Coaching, Couples, Depression, Family, Grief, Pornography, Pre-marriage, Human Trafficking

New Beginnings Therapy Services | York, PA

- Counselor: 2012 2014
 - Anxiety, Addictions, Couples, Depression, Family, Grief

Uxbridge Church of the Nazarene | Uxbridge, MA

- Associate Pastor of Marriage and Family Counseling: 1996-1999

Music Minister: 1991-1999Youth Pastor: 1991-1996

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Nazarene Strengths Institute

- Certified Coach: 2016

Prepare and Enrich Marriage System

- Certification: 2015

University of Maryland

Critical Incident Stress Management, Individual Crisis Intervention: 2009

Church of the Nazarene

- Ordination: 1994

Massachusetts General Hospital

- Clinical Pastoral Education, extended unit: 1991

EDUCATION

Eastern Nazarene College | Quincy, MA

- Master of Arts in Pastoral Counseling: 1991
- Bachelor of Arts in Religion: 1987

Rev. David S. Vatral

16531 Susquehanna Trail South, New Freedom, PA 17349 dvatral@trailnaz.org

Cell: (717) 683-8971 Home: (717) 227-1322

REFERENCES

Mr. Dan McCabe

- 68 West Street, Milford, MA 01757
- (508) 473-5289
- daniel.g.mccabe@enc.edu

Rev. Dr. Dennis King

- 1340 Crest Rd, Reynoldsburg, OH 43068
- (607) 972-7619
- pastordennis128@gmail.com

Rev. Dr. Art Roxby

- 11 NW Salevan Rd, Milford, DE 19963
- (302) 393-3967
- revart@comcast.net